Ho Chiok Yew (C.Y. Ho)

Johor Bahru, Johor, Malaysia +60187910515 cyho2212@gmail.com linkedin

SUMMARY

Born and raised in Malaysia before my undergraduate studies, I graduated with a double degree in Electrical Engineering and Economics from National Taiwan University. I have developed a strong academic foundation and practical experience in various fields, including recommendation systems, language processing, data mining and social sciences. Keen on exploring research opportunities in social computing and human-centered NLP, with a focus on combining NLP and data mining techniques with social science theories and heuristics to better understand human behavior and interaction.

EDUCATION

NATIONAL TAIWAN UNIVERSITY (NTU)

GPA: 3.99/4.30 (88.83%), or scaled to 3.83/4.00 | Sept 2019 - Jun 2024 | Taipei

B.S. IN ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING, COLLEGE OF ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING AND COMPUTER SCIENCE

B.A. IN ECONOMICS, COLLEGE OF SOCIAL SCIENCES

EXPERIENCES

IDSSP LAB (INTERDISCIPLINARY DATA SCIENCE AND SIGNAL PROCESSING LAB), NTU

Feb 2021 - Jun 2024 | Taipei

UNDERGRADUATE RESEARCHER (UNDER THE SUPERVISION OF PROF. CHE LIN)

• Studied and worked on a temporal and contextual trend-aware transformer-based push notification recommendation system that allows news platforms to disseminate articles to users through push notification services (PNS) by considering user's temporal and contextual preferences with the interplay of short-term global preferences (a collaborative work with partnering company AviviD).

INSTITUTE OF INFORMATION SCIENCE, ACADEMIA SINICA

Jul 2022 - Sept 2023 | Taipei

RESEARCHER INTERN AND PART-TIME RESEARCH ASSISTANT (UNDER THE SUPERVISION OF PROF. DE-NIAN YANG)

- Participated in research project of a graph-based user recommendation system applied in the extended reality (XR) spatiotemporal social network that aims to maximize overall user preference utility and visibility based on users' trajectories.
- Conducted research and implementations of diffusion model applied on conditional social network graph generation.

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES Experienced: Python Familiar: R | C/C++ | MATLAB

FRAMEWORKS & LIBRARIES Numpy | Pandas | Scikit-learn | PyTorch | LATEX

LANGUAGES Native (Bilingual): Chinese | English Fluent: Cantonese | Malay Beginner: French

SELECTED PROJECTS __

PROGRESSIVE KNOWLEDGE DISTILLATION FOR SPEECH SEMI-SUPERVISED LEARNING (SSL) MODELS

Jan 2023

RESEARCH PROJECT FOR THE COURSE 'DEEP LEARNING FOR HUMAN LANGUAGE PROCESSING' INSTRUCTED BY HUNG-YI LEE

• Investigated the effectiveness of performing knowledge distillation by progressively distilling the forefront hidden layers in speech SSL models to a truncated student model on the evaluation performance in SUPERB benchmark tasks.

TRANSITIONING FROM OPEN-DOMAIN DIALOGUES TO TASK-ORIENTED DIALOGUES

Jun 2022

FINAL PROJECT FOR THE COURSE 'APPLIED DEEP LEARNING' INSTRUCTED BY YUN-NUNG CHEN

• Designed an automated conversational agent to attentively detect potential intents in utterances and perform gradual transitions to fulfill the task of interest such as closing a sale within the conversation by tackling the trade-off in conversational naturalness, relevance and aggressiveness (ranked 6/40 overall in peer manual evaluation).

OPTIVER REALIZED VOLATILITY PREDICTION

Jul 2021

PARTICIPATION IN KAGGLE COMPETITION AS A SUMMER ORIENTATION WORKSHOP ORGANIZED BY IDSSP LAB, NTU

- Performed pre-processing of financial data in Python and implemented various machine learning and deep learning models for stock price realized volatility prediction such as gradient-boosting decision trees and neural networks.
- Studied and experimented with various financial and statistical indicators for further improvements in model prediction performance.

TEACHING ASSISTANCE

• Linear Algebra (2023 Fall, instructed by Hung-yi Lee), NTU.

ACADEMIC PARTICIPATION

- Machine Learning Summer School (MLSS2021), Taipei, Taiwan.
- · A Brief Discussion on Brownian Motion and Related Processes with Applications (NCTS2023), Taipei, Taiwan.

RELATED COURSEWORK/MODULES

PROGRAMMING/CS Computer Programming (with Lab) | Algorithms | Data Structures | Computer Architecture

MATH/STATS/SP Calculus (1-year) | Differential Equations | Linear Algebra | Discrete Mathematics | Game Theory

Statistics and Econometrics (1-year) | Probability and Statistics | Signals and Systems

ML/DL/DS/AI Machine Learning* | Applied Deep Learning* | Deep Learning for Human Language Processing*

Data Science and Social Inquiry * | Application of Big Data System*

Principles of Economics (1-year) | Microeconomics (1-year) | Macroeconomics (1-year) **ECONOMICS**

FINANCE Investment Theory | Financial Market and Derivatives | Corporate Finance | International Finance

Financial Engineering** | Predicting Financial Crises** | Futures and Options*

Introduction to FinTech* | Introduction to Decentralized Finance* | Blockchain and Big Data* **FINTECH**

AWARDS/HONORS

- NTUEE 1960 Alumni Scholarship, NTU, 2020-2022 (3 consecutive academic years).
- NTU Hope Bursary, NTU, 2020-2022 (3 consecutive academic years).
- Overseas Student Outstanding Academic Performance Award (Class of 2023), Overseas Community Affairs Council (OCAC).

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES _

NATIONAL TAIWAN UNIVERSITY MALAYSIAN STUDENT ASSOCIATION (NTUMSA)

Sep 2019 - Sep 2021 | Taipei

SOCIAL MEDIA AND INFORMATION COMMITTEE

- Managed social media platforms for the Association via content creation and inquiry responses.
- Disseminated information from school authorities to members via social platform posts.

PUBLICATIONS AND MANUSCRIPTS

- [ICDE'24] Bing-Jyue Chen, Chiok Yew Ho, De-Nian Yang. 2024. "AFTER: Adaptive Friend Discovery for Temporal-spatial and Social-aware XR," in 2024 IEEE International Conference on Data Engineering (ICDE).
- [ICASSP'24] Chu-Chun Yu, Ming-Yi Hong, Chiok-Yew Ho, Che Lin. 2024. "PUSH4REC: TEMPORAL AND CONTEXTUAL TREND-AWARE TRANSFORMER PUSH NOTIFICATION RECOMMENDER," in 2024 IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing (ICASSP).
- [arXiv:2311.01729] Jui-Yi Tsai, Ya-Wen Teng, Ho Chiok Yew, De-Nian Yang, Lydia Y. Chen. 2024. "CDGraph: Dual Conditional Social Graph Synthesizing via Diffusion Model," available as arXiv preprint.